[Music]
Hello everyone and welcome to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and sometimes
you're just tired of work, you're tired of
everything, you want to go
somewhere for a nice romantic weekend,
you take a holiday or a getaway.
That's right so why don't we take a
look at this word on vocabulary preview.
Very cabaret-y preview.
Okay so Marco the word
I mentioned is getaway.
It has a couple of different
meanings in English.
What are we talking about today?
Well to get away from someone would be to
like leave right to try and stay far away.
But a getaway so
taking it as a noun in
romantic getaway is
actually to take a holiday
or romantic escape from the city,
escape from your daily normal life.
That's right so it's usually
kind of brief or sudden.
Almost like you're just going to sneak
out and then come back in a couple of days.
Exactly so many people
refer to them as island
getaways if you go to an
island or a romantic getaway
if you have a romantic two-day
vacation or something like this.
Right and what are you getting away from?
You're getting away from
work, you're getting away from
the busyness of the city,
you're getting away from noise.
It's a nice way to get into the
countryside or as you said the islands.
Exactly so I think we can
take a look at our dialogue.
We actually we're going
to a travel agency called
getaway tours and we're going to try and
see if we can book a nice romantic getaway.
Welcome to perfect getaway
tours, how can I help you?
I would like to plan a surprise
getaway for me and my wife.
Very well we have a
couple of different options
such as beaches, the
wilderness, the countryside
or even going to a
spa for the weekend.
I think something in the
countryside would be nice.
Perfect, this package includes
round trip flights to New Hampshire.
A free airport pickup is included, our VIP
limousine will pick you up and provide you
with complimentary
champagne and finger food to
soften the 30 minute
ride to the countryside.
Sounds good, what does the
hotel that we'll be staying at like?
That is the best part.
Your hotel is actually
an old country villa
that has been restored
and refurbished to accommodate
a maximum of 10 guests.
You will enjoy an intimate and private
time in this very spacious and warm hotel.
Included in the prize is three
meals a day, excluding beverages.
You can choose to eat
at the fabulous restaurant
that offers a stunning view
of the lush green gardens.
Or if you prefer, your own
private spotler can arrange your
meals to be served in your
room or outside on our terrace.
Wow, this sounds like something
my wife would really enjoy.
Are there any outdoor
activities we can take part in?
Of course, the hotel has
a stable with beautiful
stallions for a very romantic
horseback ride along
the country trail. You
can also be fishing at
the nearby lake or
visit the local vineyard.
I'm sold, I want to book this
trip, I don't care what it costs.
Money is no object.
All right, we're back, so I think
this sounds pretty romantic, right?
It sounds too good
to be true, it's perfect,
they have butlers and
food and horseback riding.
That's right, so she
actually mentioned a
couple of interesting
words there describing
where they're going to go or how
they're going to spend their time.
So why don't we take a look at
those now on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Okay, so the first word
has to do with where this
couple is going, they're
going to the countryside.
That's right, the countryside, so
what exactly is the countryside?
Well, countryside or the
country is the opposite
of the city, so it's
anywhere that is rural
or less developed than a
city, not big skyscrapers or
businesses or big towns,
it's actually pretty quiet.
Okay, so usually the
countryside will have a
lot of natural wildlife
trees, gardens or farms,
I think can be considered
part of the countryside.
Definitely.
And so, yeah, that's basically the
complete opposite from the city, right?
Yes, and that's why a lot of
people take getaways to the
countryside because it's as far
away from the city as you can go.
Okay, very good.
And to get to the
countryside, they're actually
taking a round trip
flight to New Hampshire.
All right, so round
trip is an important
vocabulary item when
we're talking about travel,
because you can use this for train
tickets, flight tickets, even boat tickets.
It means that you're going there and you're
coming back, it's basically two tickets.
Right, so the opposite would be if you
buy one way ticket or a one-way flight.
That's right, so many people dream
of buying a one way ticket to the island.
You know, they never have
to come back, but round
trip means you're going to
come home at some point.
Okay, so they're actually
going round trip to
New Hampshire and also
they are getting picked up
at the airport where
they're going to have a nice
limo that's going to offer them
complementary champagne and finger foods.
Okay, my favorite kind of champagne.
Complimentary.
That's right, this means that
they're not going to pay for it, right?
It's free.
So it's the company is going to pay for it.
You can have complementary food,
you can have complementary service.
These are basically things that
someone else is providing for you.
You don't have to pay for them.
Yeah, even on talking
about flights, sometimes
people will get a complementary
upgrade to first class.
That means they are getting
a better service for free.
Not me.
Hey, if you're a work for an
airline, I would love complementary.
A complementary bump to first
class, and what about this finger foods?
What about that?
That sounds kind of strange.
Yeah, it might sound disgusting,
but it's not actually fingers that you eat.
It's food that you can
eat with your fingers.
So they're like small little treats
or snacks that you can have.
Exactly.
Usually if you go to a cocktail party or if
you go to a party at a museum or an event,
they'll have these little little
foods that you can pick up and eat.
You don't need a fork or a spoon.
Okay, so they're very
small, convenient little snacks
that you can just pick at
and pop into your mouth.
And pop into your mouth.
All right, and all of this
they're doing because
they have a 30 minute
ride to the countryside,
so they want to soften
the 30 minute ride.
Okay, so to soften something means to
make it more enjoyable or more pleasurable,
because oh no, the 30
minute ride is so rough, so hard.
So this makes it better.
Okay, so yeah, you can soften things
such as the ride to the countryside,
or you can even soften someone up.
So maybe give them some nice
compliments so they'll be nice to you.
That's right, to soften.
Okay, all right, so why don't we take a
break and listen to the dialogue again,
and we'll be back with
language takeaway part two.
Welcome to Perfect Getaway Tours.
How can I help you?
I would like to plan a surprise
getaway for me and my wife.
Very well, we have a couple of different
options, such as beaches, the wilderness,
the countryside, or even
going to a spa for the weekend.
I think something in the
countryside would be nice.
Perfect, this package includes
round trip flights to New Hampshire.
A free airport pickup is included.
Our VIP limousine will
pick you up and provide
you with complimentary
champagne and finger
foods to soften this 30
minute ride to the countryside.
Sounds good.
What does the hotel that
we'll be staying at like?
That is the best part.
Your hotel is actually
an old country villa that
has been restored and refurbished to
accommodate a maximum of 10 guests.
You will enjoy an intimate and private
time in this very spacious and warm hotel.
Included in the price is three
meals a day, excluding beverages.
You can choose to eat
at the fabulous restaurant
that offers a stunning view
of the lush green gardens.
Or if you prefer, your
own private butler can
arrange your meal to be served in
your room or outside on our terrace.
Wow, this sounds like something
my wife would really enjoy.
Are there any outdoor
activities we can take part in?
Of course, the hotel has
a stable with beautiful
stallions for a very romantic
horseback ride along the country trail.
You can also go fishing at the
nearby lake or visit the local vineyard.
I'm sold.
I want to book this trip.
I don't care what it costs.
Money is no object.
All right, we're back
and now we are going
to take a look at a
good group of adjectives
that the travel agent
used to describe how
great this hotel is,
how great the place is.
Language takeaway.
Okay, so the person on
the telephone representing
the travel company is
trying to sell something.
So she is using these
really, really great
adjectives to make
everything sound awesome.
And one of the first
things she says is that
you will enjoy an intimate and
private time in this great hotel.
Okay, so in intimate time, if something is
intimate, it means it's very, I don't know.
It usually means like romantic, right?
Romantic cozy, but also private.
So something that is intimate
is usually between two people.
Okay, so if they're going
to have an intimate and
private room, that means
it's a room only for them.
Yes, or if someone has
an intimate relationship,
that means that they're
romantically involved.
Okay, and the travel agent went on to
describe how fabulous the restaurant is.
So this adjective is really nice, fabulous.
And I think you have to
say it like that fabulous.
So this means that it's
just a wonderful restaurant.
And some people even say totally fab.
Okay, can you describe someone
as fabulous, not really, right?
He is so fabulous.
She is fabulous.
Really, you can say it all the time.
Yeah, so it also depends
on, I think, your personality.
This is a very, very descriptive word.
So sometimes it's a bit too strong.
You have to be careful.
But yeah, you can describe a person.
You can describe a place.
You can describe a thing
with the word fabulous.
All right.
Apart from having
this fabulous restaurant,
they also have a stunning
view of the gardens.
All right, stunning is similar to the word
breathtaking or shocking in a good way.
It makes you really, really impressed
because it's so beautiful or so unique.
Okay, so for example, the views, the
view of the beach is stunning, right?
Or even someone, you can
say, wow, you look stunning.
That's right. So this is a really
great compliment, by the way.
Usually men say this to women.
Okay. Women don't say this to men.
Okay. You can describe
someone's clothes as stunning.
Like her dress was stunning at the Oscars.
But if your man trying
to give a woman a
good compliment,
believe me, this one works.
You look stunning.
All right.
Okay. Nice little tip there.
Using the adjective stunning.
Okay. Now, lush.
We have lush green
gardens. So we're looking, we
have a stunning view of
the lush green gardens.
This word lush.
Lush usually describes things that
are organic, like plants and flowers.
Mm-hmm.
And we say this to mean that something
is very green, very healthy, very full.
Okay. So an apple tree, the
full with apples and you have a,
it just looks great.
You would say it's a lush apple tree.
Right. Or I could even
say, I've heard that
the rainforests of
Ecuador are very, very lush.
Okay. Hey, green.
Yeah, exactly. All right. So lush, the
very abundant, very green, very healthy.
And apart from these adjectives, the sales
agent also described that the country villa
had recently been restored and refurbished.
So what about these two words?
Restored and refurbished.
Okay. Basically, what she's saying
is that this house, this big villa,
was recently completely
remade on the inside.
Okay. So the appearance,
the look doesn't really change.
It's still an old
beautiful villa,
but maybe the insides were
old or needed to be updated.
Mm-hmm. And so that means that the
plumbing, the lights, the walls, the paint,
that with all restored,
maybe to look like
the original, very, very
beautiful and clean.
Mm-hmm. But also it
was refurbished, which
means that the fittings
and the carpet and the,
maybe the lights and all the
furniture, that was also new again.
Okay. So we usually hear
about this sometimes in
the news when they are
restoring an old church
or an old building. That
means they're making
it, they're trying to
save it and make it look
like it used to.
They're not changing it, right?
They're not trying to
make it look new, but
they're trying to make it look like it
used to look before it got old. Okay.
You know how sometimes old
things are worn and they're not,
they're not pretty
anymore. Well, what they're
trying to do is make
it really shiny and
beautiful. And refurbished
is basically to give
it, as you said, new, new
carpet or sometimes new
furniture or stuff like that. So many
people refurbish their homes, right?
That's right. And it's a
very, very popular thing
to do with, with older
houses. You buy them,
you fix them, you restore
them, you refurbish
them so that you can
want to live in them.
Right. Okay. So a lot
of great things from
this dialogue, I think
we should listen to it
one more time and
we'll be back in a little bit.
Welcome to Perfect Getaway Tours.
How can I help you?
I would like to plan a surprise
getaway for me and my wife.
Very well. We have a
couple of different options,
such as beaches, the
wilderness, the countryside,
or even going to a
spa for the weekend.
I think something in the
countryside would be nice.
Perfect. This package
includes round trip flights
to New Hampshire. A free
airport pickup is included.
Our VIP limousine will pick you up and
provide you with complimentary champagne and
finger foods to soften
the 30 minute ride to
the countryside. Sounds
good. What is the hotel
that we'll be staying at
like? That is the best part.
Your hotel is actually an old country villa
that has been restored and refurbished
to accommodate a
maximum of 10 guests.
You will enjoy an intimate
and private time in this
very spacious and warm
hotel. Included in the
surprise is three meals a
day, excluding beverages.
You can choose to eat
at the fabulous restaurant
that offers a stunning view
of the lush green gardens.
Or if you prefer,
your own private
butler can arrange your meal to be served
in your room or outside on our terrace.
Wow, this sounds like something
my wife would really enjoy.
Are there any outdoor
activities we can take part in?
Of course. The hotel has a stable with
beautiful stallions for a very romantic
horseback ride
along the country trail.
You can also go fishing
at the nearby lake or visit
the local vineyard. I'm
sold. I want to book this trip.
I don't care what it
costs. Money is no
object. All right. So
talking about getaways.
Now the sales agent
offered him options such as
beach, wilderness,
countryside, or even a spa.
Which one do you
prefer? Wilderness. For sure.
So you want to go into
the forest, the jungle. Yes.
I hate to say it. I think
beaches are boring.
Sorry, mom. I
know. I love beaches.
I like to do stuff when I'm
away. So I love the desert too.
But the wilderness is
somewhere where I'm outside.
I live in a city. I don't
want to go to a city.
So I like to go somewhere
where I can walk
around hike, ride a
bike, do things like that.
What about you? I
actually I don't have a like a
favorite actually.
Sometimes it's nice for me to
go to the beach and
relax. I do tend to get a
little bit bored after
maybe two days of doing
nothing on the beach.
But it is that does give a
good opportunity to do
other things. Beach activities
like snorkeling or scuba diving,
which can also be really fun.
But definitely I do enjoy the
wilderness as well. The jungle and
rafting or camping. Yeah, it's good fun.
The the insects can be
a bit of a of a nuisance at
times or the rain or the rain,
camping in the snow or the rain.
Yeah, horrible. But other than that, yeah,
it's great. I know not many people enjoy
these types of outdoor getaways. But
but of course, you know that you have spas.
I know some many people
enjoy going to a spa having a
mud bath and nothing
wrong with that getting your
nails done having massage. I mean getting
the whole royal treatment like me say.
So this is what we want to
know now is well, when you go on
vacation, what do you
like to do? Do you like to
get away to the tropical
beaches? Do you like to go
to the islands or the
jungle? What do you like to
do? Let us know. Our
website is EnglishPod.com.
We hope to see
you there. All right.
We'll see you guys
next time. Bye. Bye.